Maria Silva

Swampscott, MA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Maria-Silva/3f22058c19b16ebe

Business & Technology Consultant with experience in business development and project planning in several technological areas. An entrepreneurial mindset with the ability to help customers succeed. A critical thinker and an innovative problem-solver with an eye on results.

Key Skills:

- Business development.
- Business analyst.
- Marketing strategy.
- Budget management.
- Customer service.
- Project management: experience developing the project plan, scope and assigned resources to tasks.
- Computer Skills: Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, and PowerPoint) and Microsoft Project.
- Language Skills: Fluent in English, Portuguese and intermediate in Spanish.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hewlett-Packard Account Sales Representative

MarketSource - Boston, MA - November 2016 to Present

- Drive product sales at assigned events through customer interaction.
- Educate customers and associates on why HP is the best choice for customers.
- Product demonstration, merchandising, marketing, and advertising.

Inventory Associate

RGIS - Retail Grocery Inventory Service, LLC - Utica, NY - December 2015 to April 2016

- Physical inventory (sales floor & backroom, single and multi quantity).
- Performing a set of processes to ensure inventory accuracy.

Manager, Department of Entrepreneurship and Technological Development

Taguspark S.A. (A company that develops, promotes and manages a Science and Technology Park and a Business Incubator, Lisbon, Portugal) - February 2011 to February 2015

- Created a Business Incubator for tech startups: researched the market and developed the manual and regulations, the selection process of startups, the business model, the budget structure and the services to be provided (consulting services, office and laboratory spaces for lease).
- Developed and executed a building renovation with 21,000 Sq. Ft. to accommodate office spaces and biotech laboratories for startups within \$1M budget and meeting one-year deadline.
- Reduced annual operating costs by 15% through contract negotiation with laboratory equipment suppliers: increased the amount of services without any extra costs on the first two years and merged multiple equipment agreements under the same supplier on the following year.
- Increased the number of customers (occupancy rate up to 75%) through performing business presentations in universities, research centers and entrepreneurial events.
- Improved the marketing strategy by redesigning the website and the social media accounts (Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, AngelList and Google+).

- Improved customer satisfaction by anticipating their business needs: identified commonly beneficial synergies with technological companies, investors and universities and negotiated a pricing plan based on success fee with two companies that provide fund raising services.

Junior consultant

Multisector (A Consultant Company in Strategy, Technology Innovation and Industrial Management, Lisbon, Portugal) - January 2009 to February 2011

- Increased the investment in R&D projects and technology transfer between companies and universities through applying to national and European funds.
- Successfully enhanced access to national and European funds: identified the technological innovation of the R&D projects and developed the project plan, scope and assigned resources to tasks by implementing the project management best practices.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Course in Project Management

School of Economics and Management from the Technical University of Lisbon, Portugal 2010 to 2011

MS in Physics Engineering

School of Engineering from the Technical University of Lisbon, Portugal 2006 to 2008

BS in Physics Engineering

School of Engineering from the Technical University of Lisbon, Portugal 2002 to 2006

SKILLS

Project Management (2 years), Microsoft Project (2 years), Business Analysis (3 years), Consulting (6 years), Budget Management (4 years), Business Development (4 years), Entrepreneurship (4 years), Innovation (4 years), Social Media Marketing (4 years), Customer Relationship Management (4 years), Customer Satisfaction (6 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Summary Qualifications:

- Ability to organize, prioritize and work in a fast-paced environment;
- Multi-tasking and attention to details;
- Strong working relationships with customers and executive management;
- Ability to manage multiple projects with pre-allocated budget and achieve project goals;
- Strong strategic and analytical skills;
- Decision making, critical thinking and innovative problem-solver;
- Ability to take new challenges and adapt to new business realities.